Guide to the Cornell University examinations, 1869-1931.
Cornell University examinations,
- Series I. Examination Questions - Assorted
  - Differential Calculus, 1878-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 6 Sibley; 6 questions; question 1 begins: "What is meant by the Derivative of a function?"; initialed L.A.W
  - Calculus - Winter Term, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "What is meant by a Differential, …"; initialed L.H.Potter at the bottom
  - Differential and Integral Calculus, 1878-12-16 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m. - 11 a.m.; 3 Sibley Building; 6 questions numbered with Roman numerals; question 1 begins: "Annotate Articles 322 and 323 Differential Calculus."; initialed L.A.W.
  - Differential and Integral Calculus, 1877-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in very light green ink; 8 a.m.; 3 Sibley; 6 questions; initialed L.A.W
  - Integral Calculus, 1879-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in very light green ink; 8 - 11 a.m.; 7 questions
  - Differential Calculus, 1879-06-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; 6 Sibley; 6 questions; initialed L.A.W
  - Trigonometry, 1883-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 - 6 p.m.; annotated; 6 questions but two questions are numbered 5; loose page
  - Botany, Methods of Study - none complete, 1887-04-04 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten notes; appears as outline of lectures; loose page
  - Calculus, 1880-03-26 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 8 a.m.; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Define a function; a limit; …"
  - Calculus and Analytic Geometry, 1881-12-12 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 - 11 a.m.; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Define the integrals …"
  - Example Questions, Shades, Shade and Perspective - Fall Term, 1879-12-19 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; 7 questions; figure of a house and sun at the bottom right corner
  - Examination Questions, Descriptive Geometry - Fall Term, 1880 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in light purple ink; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the intersection of a cylinder and sphere …"
  - Examination Questions, Descriptive Geometry - Fall Term, 1881 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the intersection of an oblique plane …"
  - Exam. Analytical Mechanics, Juniors, 1878-03-27 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 4 questions; detailed drawings
  - Exam. (practical) Analytical Mechanics, 1878-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 5 questions; detailed drawings
  - Exam. Weisbach's Mechanics, Juniors, 1878-05-20 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Exam. Weisbach's Mechanics Numerical Problems, Juniors, 1878-05-24 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 2 questions; detailed drawings
  - Examination (theory) in Analytical Mechanics, 1878-12-14 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Exam. (practical) Weisbach's Mechanics, Seniors, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 3 questions; detailed drawings
  - Examination in Analytical Mechanics Numerical Problems, 1879-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 11 a.m. to 1:30 p.m.; detailed drawings; note at bottom of exam in pink ink: "N.B. The class in Hydraulics of next term will please look over pp. 712 - 718 (incl.) for Friday, I.P.C. (Jan 9th 1880)
  - Examination in Analytical Mechanics, Theory, 1880-03-22 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 4 questions; corrections made in what looks like blue colored pencil;; detailed drawings
  - Examination in Hydraulics, Theory, 1880-03-22 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; detailed drawings; 4 questions
  - Examination in Hydraulics, Numerical Problems, Seniors in Civil Engineering, 1880-03-23 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; detailed drawings; 2 questions
  - Examination in Analytic Mechanics Numerical Problems, 1880-03-24 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 3 questions; question 1 begins: "At a certain instant of its motion in its curved path, …"
  - Examination in Mechanics Theory, 1880-05-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; detailed drawings; 3 questions
  - 2nd Examination, Weisbach's Mechanics, Juniors, Numerical Problems, 1880-05-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 2:30 p.m. - 5:00 p.m.; detailed drawings; 2 questions
  - First Examination. Mechanics of Engineering, 1882-03-20 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in light purple ink; 3 questions; question 1 begins: "Required the strains in the three upper pieces."
  - Second Examination (Numerical Problems) Mechanics of Engineering, 1882-03-22 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 2 questions; question 1 begins: "Required the stresses in the pieces A, B, and C"
  - Original Designs, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 5 different drawings in squares; drawn in purple ink; at the bottom, upside down: "(Name) No. 6"
  - Civil Engineering, 1879-12 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in light purple ink; 3 pages; 8 questions numbered with Roman numerals; 6 additional notes numbered under Roman numerals (I - VI)
  - Cornell University, Exam. Questions, R.R. Surveying, 1880-05-20 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Give the method of adjusting the vertical …"; initialed Robert A. Pance
  - Stone Cutting, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; could not completely decipher original title; 10 questions numbered with Roman numerals
  - Engineering, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; could not completely decipher original title; 10 questions numbered with Roman numerals; initialed R.A. Pance
  - Questions for Examination in Geodesy - Winter Term, 1880 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in light purple ink; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Describe the secondary base …"
  - Questions for Examination in Geodesy - Winter Term, 1881 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in light purple ink; 8 questions; question 2 begins: "Give some of the practical tests of ..."
  - Cornell University - Examination in Grammar, 1872 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1: "State the different ways of forming the plural in English nouns."
  - The Cornell University - Examination in Grammar, 1873-09-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Explain the use of the Verb, the Adjective, …"
  - The Cornell University - English Grammar, 1875 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 20 questions; question 1 begins: "Write a short account of yourself in grammatical sentences"
  - Examination in Grammar, 1877-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 14 questions; question 1 begins: "Write a short account of yourself containing information in regard to …"
  - Questions in Geography, 1876-09-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 16 questions; annotated; question 1: "What are the tropics and where are they?
  - Cornell University - In Geography, 1877-06-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 13 questions; annotated; question 1: "Name the capital of Dacotah, of Switzerland, of Bolivia"
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Examination for Admission, 1876-06-30 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 7 questions to translate into Latin; 16 vocabulary words; question 1 for translation: "Caesar led his army into Gaul."; question 1 for vocabulary: "ducere"
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Examination for Admission, 1876-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts: I) Translate, II) Grammar; question 1 of II.: "Decline obsides, loca, superiora."
  - Latin - LIVY., Freshman, 1877-03 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts (I - III); I) Translate, II) Other questions, III) Hand in maps
  - Latin - Quintilian (Book X), Sophomore Latin, 1877-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV)
  - Latin - Q.B.F.F.Q.S. - Cato Major, and Cicero's Letter, Freshman Latin, 1878-03 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 5 parts (I - V); slightly annotated
  - Latin - The Satires and Epistles of Horace, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; two passages with a set of questions for each; first passage: Satire I, VI, 1-22; second passage: De Arte Poetica 453-476
  - Greek - Cornell University - Examination in Greek, Fall Trimester, 1875 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II) and 7 questions each question I.I: "Translate Apology, Chap. XX"
  - Greek - Greek., Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts (I - III); annotated; written at the bottom: "Return the papers"
  - Greek - Greek., Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts (I - III); 5 questions for part I; parts II and III are translations
  - Greek - Plato's Apology, Freshman Greek, 1877-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts (I - III)
  - Greek, Freshman Greek, 1877-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts (I - III); I. Herodotus, II. Homer, III. "Composition or derivation of …"
  - Greek, Freshman Greek, 1878-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV); includes Herodotus and Homer's Odyssey
  - Greek - Homer's Odyssey, Books IX and X, Freshman Winter Term, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - First Year, The Cornell University - The College of Languages, Examinations in German, Winter Trimester, 1870-04-04 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 questions (translating)
  - German - First Year, The Cornell University -College of Languages, Examination in German, Fall Trimester, 1870-1871 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 16 questions; question 1 begins: "Decline the definite article throughout."
  - College of the City of New York - Department of German Language and Literature - Examination Paper, Sophomore Class, 1871-02-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 questions
  - German - First Year, Cornell University -College of Languages, Examination in German, First Year Class, 1872-06-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - First Year, Cornell University - German Examination - The Story of Clavigo, 1873-03-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - First Year, Cornell University - Examination in German, First Trimester, 1873-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; exam in red ink; 4 parts (I-IV); question I.I begins: "Write with the definite article, …"
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Annual Examination - Junior Class, 1875-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV); slightly annotated
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Annual Examination - Junior Class, 1876-06-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Annual Examination - Freshman Class, 1876-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - First Year, Cornell University - Examination in Whitney's German Grammar and Reader, Embracing Two Terms' Work, 1877-06-13 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - First Year, Cornell University - Examination in German, First Trimester, 1877-12-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); question I.I begins: "Write, with the definite article, the nominative singular, …"
  - German - First Year - Goethe's Prosa, 1878-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II)
  - German - First Year - Examination in Whitney's Grammar and Reader, First Year - First Term, 1878-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 5 parts (I - V); part I begins: "Answer the questions, without translating the two following passages"
  - German - First Year, Cornell University, 1878-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); part I has 8 questions based on a passage; part II is translating
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Annual Examination - Freshman Class, 1873-06-11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - Examination in German, Spring Trimester, 1870-1871 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV); question I.I begins: "Translate the following into English:--"
  - German - Second Year, Cornell University - College of Languages - Examination in German, 1871-09-23 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University, 1871-03-13 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); each part has a passage to be translated and questions on that passage
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - Examinations in German, Spring Trimester, 1870-1871 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - College of Languages - German Examination, Lessing's Nathan der Weise, Fall Trimester, 1871-1872 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - Examination in German, Gɶthe's Italiänische Reise, Spring Term, 1872-1873 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, German - Examination in "Wilhelm Tell", 1877-12-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, Cornell University - Examination in German, Fall Trimester, 1876-12-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 sections both labeled "I"; first question I.I: "Write, with the definite article, the nominative singular, …"; second question I.I: "Translate into German"
  - German - Second Year, Junior German, 1876-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - German Examination, Schiller's Wilhelm Tell [For two Terms], 1875-03-13 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 5 parts (I - V)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - German Examination, Goethe's Italinische Reise, Third Term, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, The Cornell University - German Examination, Schiller's "Piccolomini," Fall Term, 1875-1876 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, Cornell University - German Examination ,"Hermann und Dorothea", 1876-03-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, German Examination, Goethe's Prosa, 1877-06-14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); both parts have a passage to be translated followed by questions
  - German - Second Year, German - Examination in "Wilhelm Tell" (Duplicate), 1877-12-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I -II)
  - German - Second Year, German - Lessing's "Nathan der Weise", 1878-01-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts(I - III)
  - German - Second Year, Scientific German, 1878-06-07 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Sheffield Scientific School - Annual Examination - Junior Class, 1878-06-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, Wilhelm Tell, 1878-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Second Year, Goethe's Prose, 1879-03 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV); part I: Sesenheim; parts 2: Werther
  - German - Second Year, German Comedy, 1879-03 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 parts (I - III); part I: From Lessing's Die Juden; part II: From Schiller's Der Baraiit; part III: From Goethe's Der Triumph der Empfindsamkeit
  - German - Second Year, Hermann und Dorothea, 1879-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV); part III divided between "For Prof. Fiske's Section" and "For Prof. White's Sections"
  - German - Second Year, Examination in German, 1879-06-11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 parts (I - IV); all 4 parts involve translating
  - German - Advanced, Senior German - Faust, 1878-06-04 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Advanced, Lessing's Nathan der Weise, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; divided into Acts (First - Fifth Act)
  - German - Advanced, Senior German - Lessing, 1878-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Advanced, Senior German - Egmont, 1879-03 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Advanced, Goethe's Faust, 1879-06-07 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - German - Advanced, Senior German - Schiller's Lyrics, 1879-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - A Page of a German Examination, 1880-03-24 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 passages to translate; original title not found
  - German Literature - Examination in German Literature, 1876-03-21 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); question I.I begins: "State what is known about the Gothic translator of the Bible"
  - German Literature - Examination in German Literature, 1877-03-21 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); part I: First Term; part 2: Second Term; question I.I begins: "Describe the character of the ancient Goth as compared with that of the Greek …"
  - German Literature - Examination in German Literature, 1877-06-09 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 12 questions; question 1 begins: "Write a sketch of Winkelmann's life"
  - German Literature, 1878-06-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 parts (I - II); question I.I begins: "Give a concise characterization of the satire in the sixteenth century"; name "Phil Barnard" handwritten on the top
  - French - Cornell University - French Department, First Year, Second Term, 1874-03-16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 17 translating questions; slightly annotated
  - French - (A B C) Cornell University - French Department, Second Year, First Term, 1876-12-14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; one passage to be translated; 5 additional translating questions; annotated on the back
  - French - Cornell University - French Department, Second Year, Second Term, 1876-03-22 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - French - Cornell University - French Department, 2nd Year, 3rd Term, 1877-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 passages to translates
  - French - The Cornell University - French Department, First Year, Second Term, 1878-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 17 questions to translate; question 1 begins: "Did you tell my brother that you are going to Paris?"; additional questions on verb conjugation
  - French - The Cornell University - French Department, Second Year, Second Term, 1878-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - French - Cornell University - Department of French, First Year, Fall Term, 1878-12-16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 14 translating questions and verb conjugations
  - French - Cornell University - Department of French, Second Year, Third Term, 1879-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - French - Cornell University - Department of French, Second Year, First Term, 1879-12-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Italian - Cornell University - Italian Examination, First Year, First Term, 1877-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 12 questions; question 1 begins: "Write the definite article before the singular and plural …"
  - Italian - Cornell University - Italian Department, First Year, First Term, 1878-12-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Italian - Cornell University - Department of Italian, First Year, Second Term, 1879-03-27 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; passage to be translated: Il Vero Amico, Atto Primo, Scena 11, Trivella, e Florindo
  - Italian - Cornell University - Italian Department, Second Year, Third Term, 1879-06-05 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Italian - Cornell University - Italian Department, First Year, Third Term, 1879-06-07 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; slightly annotated; one passage to be translated followed by questions; passage begins: "Uscito poi, e camminando di mala voglia, …"
  - Spanish - Cornell University - Spanish Department, First Year, First Term, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; list of vocabulary; 2 parts (I - II)
  - Spanish - Cornell Unversity - Department of Spanish, First Year, Second Term, 1879-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; passage to be translated followed by questions; passage begins: "Tuve particular gusto de que hubiese retrucado …"
  - Spanish - Cornell Unversity - Department of Spanish, First Year, Third Term, 1879-06-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; slightly annotated; one passage to be translated followed by questions; passage begins: "Luego que nos …"
  - English Language and Rhetoric - Syllabus, First Year, Third Term - History and Elements of English, Professor Shackford, 1877-06 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; name "Walter (?) Harvard Tap (?) '80" on the front; 12 pages and 232 questions
  - English Language and Rhetoric - History of Elements of English, First Year, Third Term - Professor Shackford, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 20 questions; question 1 begins: "Explain the terms 'bow-wow,' …"
  - English Language and Rhetoric - History and Elements of English, First Year, Third Term - Professor Shackford, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 13 questions; question 1 begins: "Give the family, the stocks of family, and the branches of the stock of languages …"
  - English Language and Rhetoric - Rhetoric, First Year, Fall Term - Professor Shackford, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 13 questions; question 1: "Show that Rhetoric is both a science and an art."
  - History - Questions for the use of Historical Students in the University of Michigan, By C.K. Adams - Professor of History, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)